Guide to the Keller Lectures collection ARCH075
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Keller Lectures collection
1954-2007
1958-1975
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
ARCH075
8.54 Linear Feet (19 containers)
The collection contains materials pertaining to the Keller Lectures from 1958-1976, including planning and publicity materials, photographs, transcripts, and recordings.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Existence and Location of Copies
A portion of the collection has been digitized, including all of the recordings in the collection. Digitized materials can be accessed at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu/explore/explore/?c=allcollections:88. Public access to the digital repository is limited to the University of Hartford Campus. Students, faculty, and staff can login anywhere with their university email and password.
Biographical Note - Alexander S. Keller
Alexander Sidney Keller was born in New York City on August 5, 1905 to Elsie Davidson Keller and Sidney A. Keller. He went to Far Rockaway High School in Long Island and later graduated from Harvard College in 1926 and the Harvard School of Business Administration in 1928. He married Carolyn Witmark in 1932. Keller settled in Hartford in 1932 to head the Pratt & Whitney Company's Keller Division, formerly the Keller Mechanical Engineering Co. of Brooklyn, founded by his father. Keller went on to become Pratt & Whitney's Vice President and General Sales Manager.
During World War II, he served on Advisory Committees for the War Production Board, the National Production Authority, and the Department of Commerce. He served as Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee of the National Machine Tool Builders Association and also on its Committee on governmental relations.
After the war, Mr. Keller and his family spent two years in Holland where, as Senior Industry Officer of the Marshall Plan Mission, he oversaw the effective allocation of three hundred million aid dollars. He was decorated by the Queen of the Netherlands for his outstanding work in reestablishing war-torn Holland on a sound economic and productive basis.
Throughout his life, Mr. Keller exhibited a sincere and profound interest in the dignity and rights of the individual. At no time was this quality so rewarding to society as when the need for refugee service was born. Founder of the Refugee Service of Hartford in 1938, he subsequently became Chairman of the Executive Committee of the National Refugee Service and as such was responsible for resettling hundreds of refugees who had escaped from Nazi Germany and from behind the Iron Curtain. He gave unstintingly of his time and effort to their problems on resettlement, housing, jobs, language barriers, emotional readjustment, and citizenship.
Mr. Keller also participated in a leadership capacity in many community activities involving social services including the Hartford Jewish Federation, Hartford Jewish Community Council, USO, Community Chest, YMCA, Girl Scouts, Symphony Society, Wadsworth Atheneum, and the American Jewish Committee. He was also a founder of the University of Hartford.
Above all came his devotion to his family and friends. It was his friends who were inspired to start this memorial to Mr. Keller. As one has expressed it so ably, "Al was a warm person who liked his fellowmen. No matter how busy his schedule he always had time to listen to someone else's problem and to extend a helping hand. His name was synonymous with good works in community endeavors."
Mr. Keller passed away on the afternoon of May 16, 1958. The Alexander S. Keller Memorial Fund, was established later that year by his family and friends, to enable the University to expose students and the interested public to the live and lively ideas and ideals of the great philosophers, writers, artists, and statesmen of their time.
[Alexander Keller biographical note is a revised version of a short biography which appeared in the 1964-1965 Keller Lecture program. This bio also includes information obtained from: "Alexander Keller Dies; P & W Co. Vice President," The Hartford Courant, May 17, 1958, http://libill.hartford.edu:2048/login?url=https://search.proquest.com/docview/553225574?accountid=11308 (accessed November 22, 2017); as well as additional information from the Keller Family]
Biographical Note - Carolyn W. Keller
Carolyn Keller was born in 1910 in Woodmere, Long Island to Viola Cahn Witmark and Isidore Witmark. Mrs. Keller attended Woodmere Academy and Wellesley College. She was a significant community leader in the Hartford area and held several leadership roles throughout her life, including chairwomen of the Citizens Committee for the Connecticut Medical-Dental School, chair of the Greater Hartford Chapter of the American Jewish Committee, secretary of the Governor's Site Selection Commission which chose the location of the UConn Health Center, and secretary of the West Hartford Charter Revision Commission, to name a few. Mrs. Keller was also a regent of the University of Hartford. When her husband died in 1958, she helped establish the Alexander S. Keller Memorial Lecture Series at the University and curated and managed the series for the next decade. In 1968, Mrs. Keller received an honorary doctorate of humane letters from the University. She passed away on July 30, 1968.
[Much of the information from this note was obtained from "Mrs. A. S. Keller Dies at 58; was UofH Regent." The Hartford Courant (1923-1991), Jul 31, 1968, http://libill.hartford.edu:2048/login?url=https://search.proquest.com/docview/549848559?accountid=11308 (accessed November 27, 2017); as well as from the Keller Family.]
Scope and Contents
The collection contains letters, memos, programs, press releases, newspaper clippings, transcripts, and recordings of Keller lecture events. The collection also contains records of the University of Hartford Committee on Keller Lectures, which includes meeting minutes, financial records, and other materials including records of two events honoring Carolyn Keller.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into five series: I. Lecture Seasons, II. University of Hartford Committee on Keller Lectures, III. Photographs, IV. Recordings, V. Duplicates.
Alexander Sidney Keller Memorial Fund Lectures; Art, French; Art -- History; China -- History; China -- Politics and government; Correspondence; Criminal justice, Administration of; France -- History -- 20th century; International organization; International relations; Lectures; Literature -- History and criticism; minutes (administrative records); Motion pictures; Nuclear warfare; Photographs; Poetry; Race relations; Sound recordings; Transcripts; Alphand, Hervé; Alsop, Joseph, 1910-1989; Armbruster, Frank E.; Aron, Raymond, 1905-1983; Berger, Gordon Mark, 1942-; Berlin, Isaiah, 1909-1997; Brée, Germaine; Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1928-2017; Cadoret, Michel, 1912-1985; Clark, Kenneth, 1903-1983; Cohen, Myron L., 1937-; Cunningham, Charles Crehore, 1910-1979; Deshingkar, Giri, 1932-2000; Eban, Abba Solomon, 1915-2002; Foster, William C. (William Chapman), 1897-1984; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006; Goldstein, Abraham S.; Gunn, Theodore; Hall, Donald, 1928-; Hoffmann, Stanley; Hofheinz, Roy, 1935-; Hu, Changdu, 1920-; Hughes, H. Stuart (Henry Stuart), 1916-1999; Isaacs, Harold R. (Harold Robert), 1910-1986; Kahn, Herman, 1922-1983; Keller, Alexander Sidney; Keller, Carolyn Witmark; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Lang, Paul Henry, 1901-1991; Lawder, Standish D.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982; McKayle, Donald, 1930-; Morgenthau, Hans J. (Hans Joachim), 1904-1980; Morot-Sir, Edouard; Moseley, Edwin M. (Edwin Maurice), 1916-1978; Myrdal, Gunnar, 1898-1987; North Atlantic Treaty Organization; Nossal, Frederick, 1927-; Oakes, John B. (John Bertram), 1913-2001; O'Grady, Gerald; Peyre, Henri, 1901-1988; Pool, Ithiel de Sola, 1917-1984; Poussaint, Alvin F.; Radzinowicz, Leon, 1906-1999; Rapoport, Anatol, 1911-2007; Read, Herbert, 1893-1968; Reischauer, Edwin O. (Edwin Oldfather), 1910-1990; Renan, Sheldon, 1941-; Riskin, Carl; Selden, Mark; Shapley, Harlow, 1885-1972; Smith, Henry Lee, 1913-1972; Snow, Edgar, 1905-1972; Spence, Jonathan D.; Stikker, Dirk U.; Sweeney, James Johnson, 1900-1986; Thomson, James Claude, 1931-; Tong, Averil; University of Hartford; Van Doren, Mark, 1894-1972; Ward, Barbara, 1914-1981; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989; Westin, Alan F.; Wilson, James Q.; Wright, Arthur F., 1913-1976; Wyzanski, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1906-1986; Youngblood, Gene, 1942-; Zagoria, Donald S.
- Lecture Seasons, 1958-2007; 1958-1976; I
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains publicity materials, planning documents, programs, and transcripts of the Keller Lectures from 1958-2007 (although the lectures ended in 1976, this series includes publicity that the lectures received years later). Recordings of the lectures can be found in Series IV: Recordings. Additional information regarding the planning of the lectures by the lecture committee can be found in Series II: University of Hartford Committee on Keller Lectures, 1958-1975.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged in order by lecture season.
  - Season 1, 1958-1959; 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
    This file contains materials including programs, advertisements, press releases, and transcripts (not all lectures have all of the aforementioned materials) for the three lectures of the inaugural season: "The Living Hand: The Role of Tradition in a Democratic Society," by Dr. Charles E. Wyzanski, Jr. (Nov. 10, 1958); "Foreign Policy and Social Change," by John Kenneth Galbraith (Jan. 12, 1959); and "The Future of Integration," by Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. (May 7, 1959).
  - Season 2, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    This file contains materials including programs, advertisements, press releases, and transcripts (not all lectures have all of the aforementioned materials) for the three lectures of the second season: "The Climate of the Cold War," by William C. Foster (Oct. 20, 1959); "Poetry as Love," by Dr. Mark Van Doren (Dec. 2, 1959); and "The Inevitability of Freedom," by Barbara Ward (Mar. 3, 1960).
  - Season 3: Twentieth-Century France: The New Enlightenment, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6, Box Shared Book Tray 2, Box 6)
    This file contains materials pertaining to the three Keller lectures, as well as the larger University convocation events of which these lectures were a part. Included are two scrapbooks which belonged to the Keller family, pertaining to the lectures and convocation. The three Keller lectures for this season were: "Albert Camus," by Germaine Bree (Nov. 28, 1960); "DeGaulle and the Fifth Republic," by Raymond Aron (Nov. 29, 1960); and "An Aspect of France and the Visual Arts," by James Johnson Sweeney (Dec. 1, 1960).
  - Season 4: The Responsibility of Power, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    This file contains materials pertaining to the three Keller lectures of the fourth season, entitled "The Responsibility of Power." The three lectures for this season were: "Alternatives to Nuclear War," by H. Stuart Hughes (Nov. 16, 1961); "Either-or Thinking," by Herman Kahn (Nov. 30, 1961); and "The Potential for Peace," by Abba Eban (Jan. 25, 1962).
  - Season 5, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
    This file contains materials pertaining to the Keller lectures of the fifth season which included: "A Reading and Discussion of His Poetry," by Archibald MacLeish (Oct. 23, 1962); "Of Stars and Men," by Harlow Shapley (Nov. 12, 1962); "Romanticism, Politics, and Ethics," by Sir Isaiah Berlin (Jan. 14, 1963).
  - Season 6, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 12-17)
    This file contains materials pertaining to the Keller lectures and performances of the sixth season including: performances by Donald McKayle and Dance Company (Nov. 25, 1963); "The Redemption of the Robot," by Sir Herbert Read (Mar. 5, 1964); and "Turner and the Liberation of Color," by Sir Kenneth Clark (Apr. 27, 1964); as well as a planned lecture by Aldous Huxley for Oct. 7, 1963 which was cancelled due to Huxley's poor health.
  - Season 7: The Shifting Western Alliance, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
    This file contains materials pertaining to the four Keller lectures of the seventh season; entitled "The Shifting Western Alliance" [The title of the convocation lectures also appears as "Shifting Western Alliances"]. These lectures include: "NATO and the Shifting Western Alliance," by Dirk U. Stikker (Jan. 4, 1965); "Alliance Strategy and the Political Issues," by Henry A. Kissinger (Jan. 5, 1965); "East-West Relations in Western Diplomacy," by Zbigniew K. Brzezinski (Jan. 6, 1965); and "The United States, France, and the Future of Europe," by Stanley H. Hoffmann (Jan. 7, 1965).
  - Season 8: Hidden Languages of the Twentieth Century, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
    This file contains materials pertaining to the eighth season of the Keller lectures, entitled "Hidden Languages of the Twentieth Century." These lectures included: "Language is More than Words," by Henry Lee Smith, Jr. (Dec. 2, 1965); "GAMES: Theoretical Experiments in Conflict and Cooperation," by Anatol Rapoport (Dec. 7, 1965); "Public Opinion and the Relations Between Nations," by Ithiel De Sola Pool (Dec. 13, 1965).
  - Season 9: China, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 1-19)
    This file pertains to the ninth season of the Keller lectures, which was a large convocation on China comprised of several lectures, discussions, roundtables, films, and even a dance performance. Speakers included Harold Jacobson, Edwin O. Reischauer, Harold Isaacs, Donald Zagoria, Arthur Wright, C.T. Hu, Jonathan Spence, Roger Clapp, Frederick Nossal, Gordon Berger, Paul Cohen, Edgar Snow, James Thomson, Giri Deshingkar, Frank Armbruster, Myron Cohen, Carl Riskin, Roy Hofheinz, and Mark Selden, and performers included Averil Tong.
  - Season 10: New Horizons for America's Cities, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20-21, Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    File contains materials pertaining to the tenth season of the Keller Lectures, entitled "New Horizons for America's Cities." The lectures for this season included: "Racial Crisis in Perspective," by Gunnar Myrdal (Mar. 12. 1968); "Race and Reality," by Alvin F. Poussaint (Mar. 18, 1968); and "Community Versus City: The New Era in Urban Problems," by James Quinn Wilson (Mar. 25, 1968).
  - Season 11, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    This file contains materials pertaining to the eleventh season of the Keller Lectures, which included, "A Sense of the Past," by Robert Penn Warren (Feb. 11, 1969) and "Technology and Imagination," by Donald Hall (Mar. 5, 1969).
  - Season 12: Black Americans Speak through the Arts, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    This file contains publicity and planning materials regarding the twelfth season of the Keller lectures, entitled "Black Americans Speak through the Arts," which was a two-and-a-half week program consisting of speakers, performers, and exhibits. The primary participants were the Eleo Pomare Dance Company, Sonia Sanchez, Etheridge Knight, Cliff Frazier, Theodore Gunn, and Jackie McLean.
  - Season 13: New Perspectives on Criminal Justice, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    This file contains the publicity and planning materials of the thirteenth season of the Keller Lectures, entitled "New Perspectives on Criminal Justice." The lectures included, "Crime and the International Context," by Sir Leon Radzinowicz (Mar. 16, 1971); "Crime, Fear and Law Enforcement," by Abraham S. Goldstein (Mar. 18, 1971); and "Legal Protection Against Crime Control Systems," by Alan F. Westin (Mar. 25, 1971).
  - Season 14: Film: Today and Tomorrow, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    This file contains the publicity and planning materials for the fourteenth season of the Keller Lectures, entitled "Film: Today and Tomorrow." The lectures included, "The Film Maker Discusses Some Recent Works," by Standish Lawder (Mar. 13, 1972); "The Cinema as Environment," by Gene Youngblood (Mar. 15, 1972); "The West Coast Independent Film and the Growth of Man," by Sheldon Renan (Mar. 20, 1972); and "Autobiography in the New American Cinema," by Gerald O'Grady (Mar. 22, 1972).
  - Season 15: The Nixon-Kissinger Foreign Policy at Home and Abroad, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 8, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder 1, Box Cassette Box 1)
    This file contains the publicity and planning materials for the fifteenth season of the Keller Lectures, entitled "The Nixon-Kissinger Foreign Policy at Home and Abroad." The lectures included: "The New Foreign Policy of the United States," by Hans J. Morgenthau (Oct. 31, 1973) and "The United States and Western Europe," by Stanley H. Hoffmann (Apr. 18, 1974 - originally had been scheduled for Oct. 18, 1973). The file also includes an unidentified wound-up red ribbon (located in cassette box).
  - Season 16: The United States on the Eve of the Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9-10, Box Shared Oversized 1, Folder 1)
    The file contains the publicity and planning materials pertaining to the sixteenth season of the Keller Lectures, entitled "The United States on the Eve of the Bicentennial." The season had only one lecturer, Alvin F. Poussaint, who had previously been a Keller lecturer in 1968. Poussaint's two-part lecture focused on oppression and repression in America and the effects of the recession on minority citizens.
  - Season 17, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    The file contains the publicity and planning materials pertaining to the seventeenth and final season of the Keller Lectures. The season's only lecturer was Joseph Alsop, who presented his lecture "Art Collecting as a Social Habit" (Oct. 27, 1976).
- University of Hartford Committee on Keller Lectures, 1958-1975; II
  This series consists primarily of the meeting minutes and financial records of the University Committee on Keller Lectures. Also, included are copies of testimonials given at a 1966 luncheon to honor Carolyn Keller for her contributions to the University and the Keller Lectures, as well as papers regarding the memorial service and estate of Carolyn Keller following her passing in 1968.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Financial Records, 1958-1975 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - University Committee on Keller Lectures Meeting Minutes, 1966 Jan 14 - 1973 Sep 19 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Testimonial Luncheon honoring Mrs. Carolyn Keller, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Carolyn Keller Memorial Service and Keller Estate, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Publicity, 1975 Mar 13 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Photographs, 1954; 1958-1974; undated; III (Box 3, Folder 18-21, Box 4, Folder 1-15)
  This series consists primarily of photographs of the Keller Lecture events and headshots provided by the speakers to the University for promotional purposes. The series also contains photographs from a memorial for Carolyn Keller on October 22, 1968.
- Recordings, 1958-1976; IV
  This series contains the recordings of the Keller Lecture events. Transcripts for some of these recordings can be found in Series I: Lecture Seasons.
  The recordings are arranged chronologically.
  - The Living Hand: The Role of Tradition in a Democratic Society; Dr. Charles E. Wyzanski, Jr., 1958 Nov 10; 1 Reels; 2 Phonographs Likely duplicate of audio reel recording, in four parts on two discs. Lacquer disc. 12in. (Box Audio Reels 1, Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1)
    This audio recording is of the first Keller Lecture. The lecture was presented by Dr. Charles E. Wyzanski, Jr. entitled "The Living Hand: The Role of Tradition in a Democratic Society." The recording includes introductions by Alan Wilson and remarks by Edward Allen.
  - Foreign Policy and Social Change; John Kenneth Galbraith, 1959 Jan 12; 4 Reels; 1 Cassettes (Box Audio Reels 1, Box Cassette Box 1)
  - The Future of Integration; Martin Luther King, 1959 May 7; 4 Reels 7 inch; 1 Reels 5 inches; 2 Cassettes; 3 Compact Discs (Box Audio Reels 1, Box Cassette Box 1, Box Shared CD Box 3)
  - Poetry as Love; Dr. Mark Van Doren, 1959 Dec. 2; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - All-Student Convocation; Herve Alphand, 1960 Nov 29; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - The Role of France Today; Raymond Aron, 1960 Nov 29; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - Algeria and the French Communaute; John B. Oakes, 1960 Nov 29; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - Class in French (in action); Germaine Bree, 1960 Nov 29; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - Hartford and France, Historic Ties; Benedict M. Holden and Jacques Chabrier, 1960 Nov 29; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - The Modern French Philosophers; Edouard Morot-Sir, 1960 Nov 29; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - DeGaulle and the Fifth Republic; Raymond Aron, 1960 Nov 29; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - All-Student Convocation, 1960 Nov 30; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - The Writer in the Fabric of History; Germaine Bree, 1960 Nov 30; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - The Emancipation of French Music; Paul Henry Lang, 1960 Nov 30; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - French Views of American Culture; Henri Peyre, 1960 Nov 30; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - All-Student Convocation, 1960 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - Developments in Electronics Engineering; Pierre Hurel, 1960 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - Developments in Atomic Engineering; DeLaage De Meux, 1960 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - French Art at the Wadsworth Atheneum; Charles C. Cunningham, 1960 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - City of Tapestries; Lawrence Jeppson, 1960 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - The Artist at Work; Michel Cadoret, 1960 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - An Aspect of France and the Visual Arts; James Johnson Sweeney, 1960 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - The Inevitability of Freedom; Barbara Ward, 1960 Mar 3; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - Alternatives to Nuclear War; H. Stuart Hughes, 1961 Nov 16; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1)
  - Either-or Thinking; Herman Kahn, 1961 Nov 30; 5 Reels (Box Audio Reels 1, Box Audio Reels 2)
  - The Potential for Peace; Abba Eban, 1962 Jan 25; 6 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - A Reading and Discussion of His Poetry; Archibald MacLeish, 1962 Oct 23; 3 Reels; 1 Cassettes (Box Audio Reels 2, Box Cassette Box 1)
  - Morning talk with Archibald MacLeish, 1962 Oct 24; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - Of Stars and Men; Harlow Shapley, 1962 Nov 12; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - Romanticism, Politics, and Ethics; Sir Isaiah Berlin, 1962 Jan 14; 3 Reels; 1 Cassettes (Box Audio Reels 2, Box Cassette Box 1)
  - Donald McKayle and Dance Company, 1963 Nov 25; 2 Reels incorrectly marked "McKayne" rather than "McKayle" (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - The Redemption of the Robot; Sir Herbert Read, 1964 Mar 5; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - Turner and the Liberation of Color; Sir Kenneth Clark, 1964 Apr. 27; 4 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - Modern Art in a Modern World; Sir Kenneth Clark, 1964 Apr 28; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
    The recording is of Sir Kenneth Clark the morning after his lecture on Turner and his use of color. The talk was a more informal discussion based on student questions on art. Despite being marketed by the University as a talk on modern art, Clark states that he is not an expert in modern art and is an art historian.
  - NATO and the Shifting Western Alliance; Dirk U. Stikker, 1965 Jan 4; 4 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - Seminar with Dirk Stikker and Henry Kissinger, 1965 Jan 5; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 2)
  - Alliance Strategy and the Political Issues; Henry A. Kissinger, 1965 Jan 5; 4 Reels; 3 Cassettes (Box Audio Reels 2, Box Cassette Box 1)
  - Morning talk with Zbigniew K. Brzezinski at Millard Auditorium, 1965 Jan 6; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - East-West Relations in Western Diplomacy; Zbigniew K. Brzezinski, 1965 Jan 6; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - Morning talk with Stanley H. Hoffmann at Millard Auditorium, 1965 Jan 7; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)